Harvey Chalmers Papers
Harvey Chalmers Papers
- Short stories (later addition)
  - The Swale Collection; Room-mates; criticism (Box 1)
    "The Swale Collection," typed carbon with pencil corrections, 23 pages
    2-page holograph criticisms of several stories, unsigned
    2-page holograph criticism by "S.C.B.", "Note on the Swale Collection"
    "Room-mates," typed first copy, 7 pages
  - Honey-Moon Mystery; Through the Looking Glass; The Grand Passion; miscellaneous (Box 1)
    3-part serial in manuscript covers
    "Honey-Moon Mystery," typed copy, 27 pages
    "Through the Looking Glass," typed copy, 27 pages
    "The Grand Passion," typed copy, 22 pages
    1-page typed letter of rejection from agent, Brandt and Brandt, dated November 9, 1936
  - Synthetic Star (Box 1)
    typed first copy, 24 pages
    typed carbon with pencilled corrections, 24 pages
  - Gentlemen of the Rapier; Parlor Trick (Box 1)
    "The Gentleman of the Rapier," typed carbon with pencilled corrections, 28 pages
    "A Parlor Trick," typed first copy, 16 pages
  - Only One Way; Mabel Elliot (Box 1)
    "Only One Way," typed first copy, 19 pages
    "Only One Way," typed carbon copy with typed corrections, 19 pages
    "Mabel Elliot," typed carbon copy, 27 pages
  - Fighting Name; Country Club (Box 1)
    "The Fighting Name," typed carbon copy, 22 pages
    "The Fighting Name," revised typed carbon copy, 17 pages
    "Country-Club," typed first copy with typed corrections, 18 pages
  - An Eye for Beauty; Funniest Thing of All; The Masterpiece (Box 1)
    Revisions of same story
    "An Eye for Beauty," revised typed first copy, 22 pages
    "An Eye for Beauty," typed carbon copy, 20 pages
    "Funniest Thing of All," second revised carbon copy, 22 pages
    "The Masterpiece," typed carbon copy, 18 pages
  - Footsteps; criticism (Box 1)
    "Footsteps," typed first copy with typed corrections, 28 pages
    "Footsteps," typed carbon copy, 25 pages
    3-page holograph criticism of several stories by M. Z. Alexander
  - Backstreet; The Sucker Look (Box 1)
    "Backstreet," typed carbon copy, 17 pages
    "Backstreet," revised typed carbon copy, 14 pages
    "The Sucker Look," typed carbon copy with pencilled corrections, 14 pages
  - Tan-Bark; Pink Lady (Box 1)
    "Tan-Bark," typed first copy, 7 pages
    "Tan-Bark," typed carbon copy, 7 pages
    "Pink Lady," typed carbon copy, 17 pages
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
    Where Friendship Ceases-published The American Field, August 31, 1935
    paper-bound volume of manuscripts (stories about P. R. Pratt, business tycoon)
    "Three Birds with One Shot," 8 pages
    "Saving the Depositors," 10 pages
    "Making He-Men," 11 pages, published in New England Sportsman, April 1933
    "The Seeds of Discontent," 10 pages
    "Bankers Holiday," 8 pages, published in New England Sportsman, May 1933
    "Belling the Cat," 22 pages
    "Blood Pressure," 9 pages, published in New England Sportsman, July 1933
    "While One True Man Remains," 11 pages, published in New England Sportsman, October 1933.
  - Change of Mind (Box 1)
    typed carbon copy with pencilled corrections, 11 pages
    Holograph introduction, 2 pages
  - Doc Barrett's Kind Heart, 3 folders (Box 1)
    typed first copy, 19 pages
    typed carbon copy, 19 pages
    revised typed first copy, 18 pages
    typed carbon copy, 18 pages
    typed first copy with pencilled corrections, 17 pages
    typed first copy plus carbon copy with pencilled corrections, 17 pages
  - Too Much Dog; The Setter Man (Box 1)
    "Too Much Dog," typed carbon copy with pencilled corrections, 11 pages, published in Field & Stream, June 1944
    "The Setter Man," typed carbon copy, 14 pages, published in Field & Stream, February 1940
  - The Sabine Women, a three-act play (Box 1)
    typed first copy, 33 pages
    typed carbon copies (two), 33 pages
  - April 1817, Chapters 1 to 7, typed copy with pencilled revisions and bound copy (mainly typed carbon copy); 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Afterglow, Parts I, II revised, Chapters 1 to 19, typed copy; Part III revised, Chapters 20 to 24, typed copy; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - West to the Setting Sun
    - Chapters 1-20, proof-read manuscript with pencilled corrections, 8 folders (Box 3)
    - Chapters 1-20, bound typewritten manuscript with typewritten corrections, 20 folders (Box 3)
  - Drums Against Frontenac
    - Chapters 1 to 11, published 1949, bound typed manuscript; typed letter to Mr. Caleb Paine, from Earle July 19, 1949 enclosed. Also memo signed "E."; 1 volume (Box 4)
    - Chapters 6, 7, 8, published 1949, bound typed manuscript with holograph correspondence; 1 volume (Box 4)
    - Chapters 9, 10, 11, published 1949, bound typed manuscript with holograph correspondence; 1 volume (Box 4)
    - Chapters 1 to 6, published 1949, bound galley proof; 1 volume (Box 4)
    - Chapters 7 to 11, published 1949, bound galley proof; 1 volume (Box 4)
- 1978 additions
  - Correspondence
    - 1846-1971 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia
    - 1935-1961, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Writings
    - Assorted pamphlets, 11 items (Box 1)
    - Books, 7 volumes (Box 1)
    - Holograph notes, 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Holograph notes, 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Research material, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Typescripts, 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Typescripts, 7 folders (Box 3)